islamicfinder.org 2017-06-19

# IslamicFinder: Accurate Prayer Times, Athan (Azan), Mosques (Masjids), Islamic Center, Muslim Owned Businesses, Hijri Calendar, Islamic Directory worldwide.

##  What is this Privacy Policy for? 

This privacy policy is for IslamicFinder's website [www.islamicfinder.org] and served by IslamicFinder and maintains the privacy of its users. 

The policy addresses the various areas where user privacy is concerned and defines the obligations and requirements of the website users, the website itself and the website owners. Moreover, the way this website protects, stores and processes user data and information will also be given in detail in this policy. 

##  The Website 

The IslamicFinder's website and it's owners take a proactive approach regarding user privacy and make sure that the necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their website browsing experience. 

##  Use of Cookies 

The IslamicFinder website uses cookies to improve the users experience while browsing/visiting the website. This website uses a cookie control system which enables the user to allow or disallow the use of cookies on their computer / device upon their first website visit. This complies with recent legislation requirements for websites to attain explicit consent from their users before leaving behind or reading files such as cookies on a user's computer / device. 

Cookies are small files that are saved to the user's computer's hard drive which track, save and store information about the user's interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website to provide its users with a personalized experience. 

In order for our users to disallow or discontinue the use and saving of cookies from this website on their computer's hard drive, necessary steps will have to be taken within their web browsers security settings which will block all website cookies and it's external serving vendors. 

This website uses tracking software to monitor it's visitors to better understand their website usage. This tracking software is provided by Google Analytics, which uses cookies to monitor visitor's usage. The software will automatically save a cookie to your computer's hard drive in order to track your engagement and usage of the IslamicFinder website, but it won't collect, save or store personal information of users. You can read Google's privacy policy for further information [http://www.google.com/privacy.html]. 

Other cookies might be saved to your computer's hard drive by external websites or vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or advertisements. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking, which typically expire within 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is saved, collected or stored. 

##  Contact & Communication 

Users who contact IslamicFinder’s website and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide personal details that are requested at their own risk. We have ensured a safe and secure form for an email submission process but we advise our users using such form to email processes that they do so at their own risk. 

This website and its owners may use information submitted by you in order to provide further information about the products / services we offer or to assist you in answering any questions or queries submitted. This includes using your details to get you subscribed to any email newsletter program the website handles but it is only done with your permission. Or if you have previously purchased from or enquired about purchasing from the company about a certain product or service that the email newsletter relates to. Your personal details are never passed on to any third parties. 

##  Email Newsletter 

This website runs an email newsletter program, which is used to inform subscribers about products and services offered by this website. Users can subscribe through an online automated process if they want to do so but do so at their own discretion. Some of the subscriptions may be manually processed through a previously written agreement with the user. No personal details are passed on to third parties nor shared with companies / people outside of the company that operates this website. 

Email marketing campaigns published and circulated by this website or its owners might contain tracking facilities within the actual email. Subscriber activity is monitored, tracked and stored in a database for future evaluation and analysis. Such monitored activity may include; the opening of emails, forwarding of emails, the clicking of links within the email content, times, dates and frequency of activity [this is by far not a comprehensive list]. This information is used to improve future email campaigns and to improve user experience. 

Subscribers are given the opportunity to un-subscribe at any time through an automated system. This process is outlined in the footer of each email campaign. If an automated un-subscription system is unavailable, clear instructions on how to un-subscribe will be relayed instead. 

##  External Links 

Although this website means to only include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised to adopt a policy of caution before clicking on any external third party links mentioned throughout this website. (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites, similar to; www.o4studio.com and O4Studio.) 

The owners of this website cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. 

##  Adverts and Sponsored Links 

This website may contain certain sponsored links and advertisements. These will usually be made available through our advertising partners, which may have detailed privacy policies relating directly to the adverts they serve. 

Clicking on any such advertisements will send you to the advertiser's own website through a referral program which may use certain cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from this website. This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on your computer's hard drive. Hence, users should note that by clicking on sponsored external links, they do so at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held responsible for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. 

##  Social Media Platforms 

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate in are in line with the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively. 

Users are advised to use these social media platforms wisely and engage with them with caution with regards to their own privacy and personal details. This website and its owners will never ask for personal or sensitive information through any social media platforms or encourage users to discuss sensitive details by contacting them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email. 

This website may use social sharing buttons, which help share certain web content directly from web pages to the social media platform being used at the time. Users are advised to be careful while using such social sharing buttons and that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may monitor, track and save your requests to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account. 

##  Shortened Links in Social Media 

This website and its owners may share website links to relevant website pages through their own social media platform accounts. By default, some social media platforms shorten lengthy urls automatically [web addresses] (this is an example: http://bit.ly/zyVUBo). 

Users are advised to take caution before clicking any of these shortened urls published on social media platforms by this website and its owners. Despite the best efforts to ensure that only genuine urls are published on the website, many social media platforms are prone to hacking and spams and hence, this website and its owners cannot be held responsible for any damages or implications caused by visiting any shortened links.
